ORIGINAL STORY WEBTOON SWEET HOME
BY CARNBY KIM AND YOUNGCHAN HWANG
SWEET HOME
I'm not going to shoot.
I'll just take the kid.
-Yi-kyung. It's me, Eun-yu.
-Get away from her!
Get over here.
Now!
See you around.
Yi-kyung.
I'm not going in there.
And I don't need your help.
Pretend you never saw me.
Wait.
I need to ask you something.
Wait!
Wait. No.
It's dangerous. Don't go.
I told you I'd kill you if you stopped me.
My baby…
My precious baby…
Are you still sick?
No, I'm not.
Yeah.
You are.
You always are.
And that makes me sad.
I know.
But…
I'm all better now.
I'm not coughing up blood anymore
and my stomach doesn't hurt.
Look, my teeth grew back too.
I'm all better now.
I need to…
help you.
No, I can do it.
Jun-il…
I'll do anything to fix you!
I…
got you your medicine.
HERBICIDE
Jun-il, this is…
If you die, you won't feel sick anymore.
What's wrong?
I'm all better now.
You go back and forth all the time.
You get better and then get sick again.
You're always like that.
Jun-il…
I'm telling you, I'm all better now.
Mom.
It'll all be over when you die.
I can do it.
I'm a good boy.
Jun-il, get a hold of yourself.
Drink it.
Jun-il…
Be quiet and drink it.
Mom.
Mom?
Are you dead?
You're not sick anymore, right?
Look, I did it.
Good job.
Why aren't you dead?
Why are you still alive?
If you don't die, you'll be sick!
Die!
Just die already!
Jun-il.
I'm sorry…
I was such a burden.
Damn it!
God damn it!
You won't find her in the dark.
She's already--
Let go!
Let go of me!
I said let go!
Let go!
I finally met her.
I can't let her go like this.
So stop getting in the way.
I swear I'll kill you
if you follow me again.
Wait.
Let go.
No.
Let go or we'll both die.
Hold on tight!
I'll pull you up on three.
Get your feet on the sides and hold on.
Wait.
There's something at the bottom.
Watch out.
I'll let go…
on three.
Stay close to the sides.
One, two, three.
It was Oh Jun-il.
I just wanted to stimulate him.
I didn't know he'd explode like this.
The blood sample
showed signs of monsterization,
but he had absolutely no symptoms.
There were signs of monsterization,
but no symptoms
such as nosebleeds or hallucinations.
I should've been more careful with him.
I finally found a specimen
and I got too excited like an idiot.
That's enough.
You must be mistaken.
What?
Oh Jun-il came to see his mom.
But the symptomatic individual
succumbed to monsterization
and killed her own son during her rampage.
You, doctor, saw and reported it,
and the Platoon subdued her.
Is that right?
Who have I been talking to?
Do you have trouble hearing?
You want me to explain it again?
Oh Jun-il became a monster
without any symptoms.
So what?
He's unlike any case we've ever seen.
Monsterization in itself
is beyond our understanding.
When you dragged me out here
and built me a fancy research facility,
I assumed you had some great purpose.
Was it all for show?
You're only half right.
I can see it in your face.
What's the big picture you have in mind?
Why do you think I kept you alive?
You're the symbol of hope…
that humans haven't given up yet.
That we may overcome this eventually.
-That's not the truth.
-The truth doesn't matter.
What matters is what you believe.
Don't shake their faith.
Or everything will fall apart.
Fuck.
Get on.
I was just trying to find him.
Aren't you coming?
Not until I find him.
Then why did you go there?
Why did you go where people were?
Don't.
Has it already been a month?
Just hang in there.
We're almost there.
Mom.
Mom?
Did you sleep here?
You didn't get much sleep.
I can see it on your face.
What are your hands for?
Are they just for putting on makeup?
Don't you know how to knock?
I…
I was just worried about you.
You can enter my room, but not here.
I'm warning you.
I'm serious.
Okay.
Go.
It's time for roll call.
Today's infectee banishment
has been canceled.
An infectee went through
monsterization last night,
and the Platoon subdued her.
Please do not be alarmed
and prepare for the roll call.
Over.
Did you catch her?
Sorry?
Yes.
It's all thanks to the Platoon
that we can sleep in peace.
It's nothing to be so excited about.
Excuse me?
A person died.
But it's a monster, not a person.
It's a fine line.
You're one unhealed wound away
from being treated the same.
Let's go.
Okay.
What was that all about?
Did you hear anything?
Not sure.
Must have been the night shift.
They would've told us.
They always brag about killing monsters.
If Tak said it happened, it happened.
He wouldn't make stuff up.
Maybe he is.
Hey.
Watch what you say, will you?
Can't you see
that we're being kept out of the loop?
I don't trust anyone
other than Sergeant Kim.
How can you say that?
Come confess your sins.
Confessions are a great excuse
to talk behind someone's back.
What happened?
She was supposed to be
released this morning.
She was supposed to be released
after meeting Jun-il!
Promises hardly mean anything these days.
What the hell?
What happened here?
Tell me what happened.
Do you know what this is?
It's Jun-il.
If I told you, would you believe me?
You said I'm the least
trustworthy person here.
You do have great insight.
Why are you getting
so worked up about her?
You weren't even that close.
Am I wrong?
Who am I talking to?
A girl?
Yes.
Ring any bells?
Not at all.
Are you sure?
Yong-seok would have told me about her.
So he didn't leave to escape then, right?
We should get him then.
I'll get the boys--
-It hasn't been approved.
-What?
What are you…
I have to see the Master Sergeant.
Hey, Seo-jin.
What?
Don't tell me you agree with him.
No, we need to find Yong-seok.
So what's the issue?
The Platoon only acts for the public good.
Yong-seok didn't go missing.
He went AWOL.
It's nothing more
than a personal mishap as of now.
So we abandon him?
You said he'd be here.
You said we could go back to find him!
Look, man.
I only came back because I trusted you.
If I knew this would happen…
I would've stayed back to find him.
We could lose all of our men
if we go out in this situation.
Yong-seok has the radio
and the transmitter with him.
Let's talk about finding him
when we get a signal.
You're a coward.
You're no different from Tak.
Out of my way.
Sergeant Kim.
Chan-yeong has gone missing.
There was also a problem
during the roll call.
There must be an exit we don't know about.
Search the whole stadium
with a team of survivors.
If you find it, block it off.
Yes, sir.
Do Sang-jin, An Dong-gi, Lee Eun-yu,
and Park Chan-yeong are missing.
Did they miss the roll call?
Yes, they all went missing.
Do Sang-jin and An Dong-gi
were unhappy with the expedition ban.
And Lee Eun-yu seems to have left
due to her circumstances.
But the main gate was never opened.
There must be another way out.
We'll find it and block it off.
All right, go ahead.
Cooperate with Chief Ji
to block off the exit.
And keep your eyes on the workers.
Sarge.
Will you keep letting Chan-yeong
do whatever he wants?
We can take disciplinary action
when he comes back.
Where's Min?
He won't leave the barracks, sir.
Go and find the exit first.
Yes, sir.
Are you Sergeant First Class Kim?
Please…
find Yong-seok.
Did you find it?
We're still searching.
So why are you here?
Three people left the stadium yesterday.
Do you know where and why they escaped?
Are you accusing me of something?
I wouldn't know.
I have no reason to hide anything.
You said there was no other exit
besides the main gate.
And now we're looking for
that nonexistent exit.
Master Sergeant Tak.
How much time do you spend
watching the CCTV every day?
You seem like you want to know
everything about this place.
The desire to be omniscient
is the beginning of dictatorship.
Although it seems you've begun already.
And what do you call it
when you withhold information
and put everyone in danger?
I know you're an important figure here.
But that doesn't mean
you can do as you like.
Is this a threat?
I'm asking for your cooperation.
Let me know if you change your mind.
She's probably dead, right?
Who?
The troublemaker from that family.
I'm talking about
the previous troublemaker, Lee Eun-yu.
Well, who knows?
She's tough as nails.
They're causing us so much trouble.
Just pretend you're looking.
If the Platoon can't find it, how can we?
Oh, right.
The Platoon's youngest soldier
disappeared with her.
Come to think of it,
it looked like those two
already knew each other.
Is that so?
Now that you mention it,
there was something
about the way he looked at her.
They must have eloped.
My goodness.
Even at a time like this, love prevails.
Why would they even elope?
It's not like the Platoon
forbids relationships.
That's true.
So they didn't elope then.
Of course not!
That's the most ridiculous thing
I've heard in my entire life.
Why would you ship
Chan-yeong with that crazy bitch?
Well, they disappeared around the same--
Shut up!
If I ever hear that nonsense again,
I'll make you pay for it.
They definitely eloped.
They ran away from her.
Be quiet.
Mom.
Mom!
Mom, where the hell is Lee Eun-yu?
Damn it.
This is how they do it in movies.
-What are you doing?
-Mom.
Were you inside?
I heard some noise inside,
so I was worried about you.
I told you not to come here.
Right, I forgot.
I'm just so upset
about Chan-yeong and Eun-yu.
I'm sorry.
I've coddled you long enough.
I let you use my name
to lord it over others.
But there isn't a line you won't cross.
-Mom…
-Get out.
Go.
Get out!
Mom.
Mom, I'm sorry.
I promise I won't do it again.
Mom, please don't abandon me.
Mom!
You shouldn't have followed me.
I had to know your secret.
It could have…
endangered the stadium.
Why would you risk your life
to protect it?
We just happen to be stuck in there.
Is it that important to you?
We have nowhere else.
To the survivors,
the stadium is their last home.
And it's the Platoon's job to protect it.
Whatever.
It's your funeral.
-I don't give a crap.
-You risked your life too.
You and I are no different.
Stay still.
Lift it up.
I'm never telling you.
I know.
You believe it's right to hide it.
So hide it.
And I'll do what I can to find out.
The day Mr. Kim died…
What you saw that day…
Was it really a monster?
It wasn't human.
That's fine.
I'm okay with that.
I initially thought
the monster killed both you and Mr. Kim.
But…
only Mr. Kim died.
And you survived.
You're right.
Something out there is protecting me.
Who is it?
I don't know.
They won't show themselves.
I'm just choosing to believe
that it's a certain person.
Who would that be?
I wish…
I wish I could see him just once.
Seeing how hard he's trying to avoid me…
I wonder if I shouldn't try to see him.
He probably has a good reason.
But I'm ready to accept him for who he is.
So just once…
No.
If it's fate…
you'll meet him.
Who's that?
Who's out there?
What if it's a monster?
As if a monster would throw us a rope.
Let me help.
All right.
One, two, three.
On my shoulder.
Help me.
You're not leaving me here, are you?
Promise me.
What?
Promise you won't follow me
or ask any questions.
I can't promise that.
You're not in a position to say that.
I can't make a promise I can't keep.
Fine, do whatever you want.
Grab it.
Hey.
Wait, something's out here.
Hurry up.
What the hell?
It's gasoline.
Watch out!
You're still alive.
You're the moles from the stadium.
You remember me, right?
From that bus to the shelter.
Of course.
I almost died, thanks to you.
Go back to where you came from
and don't go poking your noses around.
Dad.
Can we ditch that minx and keep him?
You want to take him?
-Yeah.
-What are you doing?
Can you even walk properly?
I don't need more mouths to feed.
Be on your way.
I think she has different ideas.
What are you doing?
I don't trust you.
Put it down while I'm being nice.
This?
You want it back?
I'll trade you for it.
Let me keep him.
Are you dense?
Don't you understand Korean?
You can take him!
Hey.
You need to pay for ruining my trap.
This is a straight-up robbery.
I'll open the door tomorrow,
so see yourselves out.
And don't ever come back.
-Ha-ni.
-What?
Let's go now.
On my way, boss.
-On my way.
-Untie me.
Now.
Hey!
Open up! I'm leaving now!
What difference does it make
if I leave today or tomorrow?
Open up!
Hey.
What?
Did you mean it?
When you told her
to take me away?
Just sleep.
This is crazy.
Absolutely crazy.
RUBBING ALCOHOL
There's nothing I can do now.
I'll feel worse if I think about it.
But still…
Oh Jun-il's monsterization…
It progressed way too quickly.
There weren't any symptoms either.
Damn it!
Stop thinking about it.
Just forget it.
Just empty your mind.
Don't think about anything.
Was it because of the wound?
GIRL, MOM, FLOWERS, TREE, STIMULATION
Don't you remember?
A kid.
Jun-il…
There was a kid…
What on earth did you see?
…where there were flowers
-and trees.
-Was it human?
-It was a girl.
-Was it a monster?
She pushed.
Or was it…
Mom.
Are you okay?
I'm fine.
Are you still afraid of me?
Because I hurt you back then?
Get inside.
No, I've done nothing wrong.
I'm trying to protect you.
Protect me?
You?
You're lying.
About everything.
You're just like them.
Did you…
meet people again?
Did you use your hands…
to turn them into monsters?
What's wrong with that?
They became nicer.
It happened again.
You did it again.
Why did you do it?
That's why I locked you up.
It was for your own sake.
To stop you from doing this again!
Let go!
Stay in here.
Is the monster dead?
It probably isn't.
You okay, man?
Hey.
Hey!
Mom…
No!
Stop it!
Why did you do that?
-It was a monster.
-Would you do the same to me?
No.
-Why would I--
-Because I'm a monster.
That's what you think too.
You said I wasn't,
but I'm different from you.
I know everything.
That's not true.
I didn't give birth to a monster.
Is that so?
"You were a mistake."
"You're a monster."
"I'm afraid of you."
What are you talking about?
"I wish you would disappear."
-No.
-"I can't abandon you,
so you should abandon me."
"Please go where I can't find you."
No.
You've been thinking that all along.
What are you doing?
You want to follow my brother?
Is he your brother,
your dad, or your boss?
Pick a lane.
Let's just say he's my savior.
So?
Are you going or not?
You're awake.
Where's the girl I came with?
I don't know.
She left earlier.
Where's my gun?
-Why?
-I have to go back now.
Listen.
If you try to walk around too soon,
you'll have to amputate your leg.
I'm familiar with these injuries.
It's not that bad.
Do I look like a doormat?
Excuse me?
I feed you, I give you a place to sleep,
I even care for your wound,
and now you're just going to leave?
Where are your manners?
Is that how it works in your country?
Aren't we from the same country?
No.
I'm from outer space.
Right.
Thank you for your help.
I'll repay you someday.
But I have to go now.
Fine.
But…
you should eat before you go.
Eat up.
What is this made of?
You think you're at a restaurant?
Just eat what you're given.
It doesn't look edible.
Are you worried it'll kill you?
See?
Don't ask for seconds.
Okay, thank you.
Oh, my.
What took you so long?
Stop slacking off!
Don't you see all of this?
I'm doing all the hard work for you.
You're quite carefree, aren't you?
Aren't you worried about the girl?
You came here together.
You're a cold son of a bitch, aren't you?
God damn it!
Why would I worry about her
when she's the one who chose to leave?
I've got nothing to do with her!
I don't know all the details,
but I heard she was the reason
Chief Ji let you work here.
You should be grateful.
Keep living with such a nasty heart,
and you'll turn into a monster.
Grateful, my ass.
Damn it.
This isn't good.
This isn't going to last long.
Those bastards in the Platoon
aren't what they used to be.
You better watch your mouths.
You motherfuckers.
Hey, you.
The people who used to work here
got fired because they ran their mouths.
Excuse me.
You can't just take things like that.
We risked our damn lives for this stuff!
You can't tell us what to do.
Okay.
-Not again, sir.
-You saw nothing.
Of course.
But if they report it to Tak--
For fuck's sake!
Let them!
Then I could get the hell out of here!
Come on, Sarge.
Someone might hear you.
People are already joking
about deserters being a trend.
Who the hell said that?
Yong-seok is different
from that buck Private Park Chan-yeong.
Motherfuckers.
They're only alive because of us!
Ungrateful assholes, babbling away.
Sergeant Kim's been
looking for you all day.
Tell him to fuck off.
Dying here won't get me
a medal or a hero's funeral.
We just do meaningless shit
until we all drop dead.
Fuck this shit.
This one's going to last a while.
Aren't you going to look for Yong-seok?
How did you get in here?
Why aren't you going to rescue him?
He's part of the Platoon.
He said you were family.
That's what he thought of you.
You let him go.
You should've stopped him.
You knew he could die.
So why did you let him go?
You're sick, right?
What did you need?
Why the hell did he…
disappear without saying a word?
I needed medicine.
I know my condition is terminal,
but I wanted some more time.
That's why I let him go.
I tried to stop him.
But Yong-seok
insisted he would go.
He said he'd get it for me!
Is that so wrong?
So bring him back.
Bring Yong-seok back!
What do you really want?
Him, or the medicine
that he might bring back?
Does that really matter?
Is that your answer?
BAMSEOM
Hypocrite.
You're not real.
Of course not.
The real me died that day.
The moment you strangled your own family.
How did it feel?
You enjoyed it, didn't you?
I know you enjoy…
killing people.
It's what you do best.
Just do it.
You have nothing to live for.
I do.
What?
I still have…
things to do!
No.
It's PTSD.
Post-traumatic stress disorder.
It's the only explanation.
Am I right?
I think I could help you out.
I don't like making petty threats.
But there are other names for it
such as deal,
transaction,
and even negotiation.
What do you want?
Let me out of here.
Do you understand
the significance of Jun-il's case?
It puts a huge dent in our theory
about monsterization.
It may have evolved.
You can't just sit around.
It's time to take a risk.
All the experiments failed.
And there's absolutely nothing you can do.
There's something you don't know.
I'm not saying I'm going to
treat your monsterization.
I'm going to help you fight it
so you don't turn into a monster.
You know those special infectees?
I can turn you into one.
If you go down,
this whole place will fall apart.
Didn't you say
you wanted to protect this place?
He won't attack you.
I'm looking for Yi-kyung.
You know where she is, don't you?
I need to see her.
Mom…
People…
They're all bad.
"Mom"?
You're just like them.
Subtitle translation by Ji-hun Lee
Modify by Blue-Bird™